<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Events | Parallel-in-Time]]></title>
  <link href="http://parallelintime.org/news/categories/events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://parallelintime.org/"/>
  <updated>2015-09-28T12:11:27+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://parallelintime.org/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Parallel-in-Time Enthusiasts]]></name>
    <email><![CDATA[daniel.ruprecht@usi.ch]]></email>
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Minisymposium at SIAM PP 2016]]></title>
    <link href="http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/07/23/siampp-minisymposium.html"/>
    <updated>2015-07-23T07:26:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/07/23/siampp-minisymposium</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Plans for a proposal for a PINT mini symposium at SIAM PP 2016 in Paris.</p>

<!--more-->
<p>With mini symposia related to parallel-in-time integration at</p>

<ul>
  <li><a href="http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=15471">SIAM CS&amp;E 2013</a> in Boston,</li>
  <li><a href="http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=17906">SIAM PP 2014</a> in Savannah,</li>
  <li><a href="http://meetings.siam.org/sess/dsp_programsess.cfm?SESSIONCODE=19996">SIAM CS&amp;E 2015</a> in Salt Lake City</li>
</ul>

<p>and an <a href="https://www.pathlms.com/siam/courses/1043/sections/1256">invited talk</a> by Rob Falgout also at SIAM CS&amp;E 2015, the topic has been well represented at SIAM conferences in the last years.</p>

<p>To continue these efforts, a proposal for a mini symposium on <em>parallel-in-time integration methods</em> for the upcoming <a href="http://www.siam.org/meetings/pp16/">SIAM PP 2016</a> (April 12-15, 2016) in Paris is in the planning stage. If you would like to contribute to the mini symposium with a presentation, please contact one of the organisers:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Tobias Neckel, TU Munich</li>
  <li>Daniel Ruprecht, <a href="/groups/usi.html">USI Lugano</a></li>
  <li>Martin Schreiber, <a href="http://www.parallelintime.org/groups/uoe.html">University of Exeter</a></li>
</ul>

<p>The deadline for proposals is in September, so the list of speakers will have to be finalised towards the end of August.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[First scientific committee elected]]></title>
    <link href="http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/06/26/sc-election-result.html"/>
    <updated>2015-06-26T09:21:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/06/26/sc-election-result</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The election for the scientific committee is now closed and the results available. As we had 7 candidates for 7 open positions, the outcome is not a big surprise. Nevertheless, the first election of a scientific committee will hopefully be an important milestone and help to successfully continue the PINT workshop series for many years to come.</p>

<!--more-->
<p>The following colleagues have been elected as members of the first scientific committee:</p>

<ul>
  <li>Martin J. Gander, University of Geneva, Switzerland</li>
  <li>Stefan Güttel, University of Manchester, UK</li>
  <li>Ron Haynes, Memorial University of Newfoundland, Canada</li>
  <li>Rolf Krause, University of Lugano, Switzerland,</li>
  <li>Daniel Ruprecht, University of Lugano, Switzerland (soon: University of Leeds, UK)</li>
  <li>Jacob Schroder, Lawrence Livermore National Laboratory, USA</li>
  <li>Robert Speck, Jülich Supercomputing Centre, Germany</li>
</ul>

<p><strong>Support from Michael Klöppel at TU Dresden is thankfully acknowledged</strong>: he served as the voting committee and set up and administrated the election through the <a href="https://vote.heliosvoting.org/">helios</a> online voting system.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Election of Scientific Committee]]></title>
    <link href="http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/06/26/sc-election.html"/>
    <updated>2015-06-26T09:21:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/06/26/sc-election</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The election for the scientific committee is open until July 3rd 2015, 4pm GMT.</p>

<!--more-->
<p>Following the <a href="/events/bylaws.html">bylaws</a> put in place during the workshop in Dresden in May 2015, the election of a scientific committee for the PINT workshop series is now underway. Everyone who was officially registered for one of the last three workshops (Manchester, Jülich or Dresden) is eligible to cast a vote and should have received a corresponding email from the helios online voting system.</p>

<p>In case you were registered for one of those workshops but <em>did not receive an email</em>, please contact Michael Klöppel from the voting committee at michael[DOT]kloeppel[AT]tu-dresden[DOT]de before July 2nd.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Bylaws for the PinT workshop series]]></title>
    <link href="http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/06/04/bylaws.html"/>
    <updated>2015-06-04T10:21:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/06/04/bylaws</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Bylaws for the parallel-in-time workshop series.</p>

<!--more-->
<p>With the aim to successfully continue the PinT workshop series even beyond the
<a href="/events/upcoming/2016/5th-workshop-on-parallel-in-time-integration.html">5th workshop</a> in Banff,
Canada, a set of <a href="/events/bylaws.html">bylaws</a> for the election of a scientific committee has been
put in place during the workshop in <a href="/events/past/2015/4th-workshop-on-parallel-in-time-integration.html">Dresden</a>.
The bylaws define a set of rules for the election of a scientific committee.
The committee is responsible for the coordination and promotion of the workshop series.
We are looking forward to many more interesting PinT workshops!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Successful workshop in Dresden]]></title>
    <link href="http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/06/04/dresden-postnews.html"/>
    <updated>2015-06-04T09:21:44+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://parallelintime.org/news/2015/06/04/dresden-postnews</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Successful 4th Workshop on Parallel-in-Time Integration in Dresden, Germany.</p>

<!--more-->
<p>The <a href="/events/past/2015/4th-workshop-on-parallel-in-time-integration.html">4th PinT workshop</a> in
Dresden turned out to be another great event in the <em>Parallel-in-time integration</em> workshop series:
With 40 participants from 9 different countries, this workshop again provided a lively forum for
many interesting discussions around a great many different aspects of PinT.
With several well-known researchers from the climate and atmospheric science community present,
fascinating discussions emerged about the feasibility of using parallel-in-time integration methods
in climate simulations and numerical weather prediction.</p>

<p>Moreover, in order to support the continuation of the workshop series,
<a href="/events/bylaws.html">a set of bylaws</a> has been put in place and the first election of a scientific
committee will take place within four weeks after the workshop.</p>

<p>Certainly, everybody is now looking forward to the
<a href="/events/upcoming/2016/5th-workshop-on-parallel-in-time-integration.html">5th workshop</a> in the
series in November 2016 in Canada.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
